Anita Amit Chipkar

Android Developer, Mentor, Learner





ABOUT ME

Android Developer with more than six years of experience in Software Development, Application Maintenance & Support and Project Execution. Dedicated to continuously developing, implementing, and adopting new technologies to maximize development efficiency and produce innovative applications.

CORE SKILLS

- Native Android Development with Android Studio(v-Electric Eel | 2022.1.1) and Android SDK tools.
- Architected and Developed 16+ Android
- Able to work independently.
- Proficient in Kotlin and Java 8 / Java design patterns, oops concepts.
- · Proficient in design, problem-solving and debugging.
- Version Control Systems(Git)
- Collaboration tool Jira Software

CERTIFICATIONS

Kotlin Programming

Certification by LearnCodeOnline (Sept 2020)

Diploma in Android Application Development

Certification by Spark Institute, Pune (Sept 2015 - Feb 2016)

Front End Development

Certification by Spark Institute, Pune (Mar 2016 - May 2016)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Android Developer The Appineers Pvt.Ltd,Pune

June 2021 to Jan 2023

- · Handling various technical aspects like coding of modules using the given design specifications, debugging and fixing the defects as well as analysing its root cause.
- · Worked as a part of an Agile team to develop high-quality Mobile Apps.
- Coordinating with team members for system design, integration and application maintenance.
- Improved base WhiteLabel Project and mentored juniors.

Freelance Android Developer Freelance, Pune

July 2020 to May 2021

- Involved in the full life cycle of the project including design, development, debugging, testing and deployment.
- Responsible for consuming the REST services, JSON response and parsing them to get the required information.

Android Developer

Accenture Solutions, Pune March 2020 to June 2020

- Implemented two prototypes to provide User Interface required by the client.
- Worked in an agile environment Participated in Daily standup meetings.

Android Developer

Impulse Technology & Business Solutions, Pune March 2019 to Dec 2019

- · Designed the architecture and user interface using client requirements and use-cases.
- Used Firebase Cloud Messaging for Push Notifications.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

M.Sc in Computer Science

MES Abasaheb Garware College Savitribai Phule Pune University,Pune 2015

B.Sc in Computer Science

Modern College Of Arts, Science & Commerce Savitribai Phule Pune University, Pune 2013

H.S.C

Sangmeshwar College,Solapur Maharashtra State Board 2009

S.S.C

Chaturabai Shravika Vidyalay,Solapur Maharashtra State Board 2007

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Freelance Android Developer

Freelance, Pune

Jun 2017 to Feb 2019

- Fixed bugs with code, design patterns and miscellaneous occurrences during projects.
- Responsible for the design, build, deployment, debug & maintenance of Android applications for Google Play.

Software Developer BiCS Infotech Pvt Ltd,Pune

Jun 2016 to May 2017

- Integrated Google play services and Google Maps API V2.
- Worked extensively with Android (Java) & the SDK frameworks.
- Implemented Material Design for the latest app supporting Android 5.0.

PROJECT DETAILS

Project Name	LOC https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.app.loc
Description	The LOC is the app of contractors for contractors.
Technology & Tools	Kotlin,MVVM Architecture,Dagger2,RxJava,DataBinding,LiveData,Firebase.
Duration & Team Size	04 Months & 03 Members

Project Name	Friendly Favors https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.app.friendlyfavor
Description	Friendly Favors is an app that individuals or businesses can join.
Technology & Tools	Kotlin,MVVM Architecture,Dagger2,RXJava,DataBinding,LiveData,Firebase.
Duration & Team Size	04 Months & 03 Members

Project Name	AGO App https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.goldenopportunity
Description	Career community volunteer connection app to create golden opportunities for all.
Technology & Tools	Kotlin,MVVM Architecture,Dagger2,RxJava,DataBinding,LiveData,Firebase.
Duration & Team Size	04 Months & 03 Members

Project Name	ECT https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.emotionalcoretherapy.ectmain
Description	ECT is the Emotional Core Therapy Christian Spiritual App.
Technology & Tools	Kotlin,Material Design,DataBinding,Firebase.
Duration & Team Size	03 Month & 02 Members
M.DODM	
Project Name	MyBuroCRM https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.myburocrm.myburoservicecrm
Description	MyBuro CRM is for customer service,AMC and Repairing material management.
Technology & Tools	Material Design,XML,Java,MVP Architecture,RESTFul WebServices.
Technology & Tools Duration & Team Size	Material Design,XML,Java,MVP Architecture,RESTFul WebServices. 04 Month & 03 Members

Project Name	MyAttendance https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.myattendance.myattendance
Description	myAttendance is the geolocation based attendance app.
Technology & Tools	Kotlin,MVP Architecture,Google Map,Geocoding API,RESTFul WebServices.
Duration & Team Size	02 Month & 02 Members

Project Name	Infora
Description	Book Doctor Appointment fast and simple on Infora for multiple hospitals.
Technology & Tools	XML,Java,MVP Architecture,Firebase Push Notification,Web Services.
Duration & Team Size	05 Months & 03 Members

Project Name	FMS https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.fractal.fms
Description	Project Management App.
Technology & Tools	Material Design,XML,Java,Push Notification using Firebase,RESTFul Web Services.
Duration & Team Size	04 Months & 04 Members

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the details provided by me in this resume are correct and I have knowingly not omitted/ misrepresented any information. I am aware that the company can use this data for verification purposes and any material inconsistency identified between the details shared above versus actual information would have a bearing on my employment, based upon company policies.

Place: Pune

A.A.Chipkan Anita Chipkar